{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869647.048703, "questionText": "Will most of humanity be infected by the new coronavirus ?", "answerText": "It is likely that eventually it will become endemic , and most of us will get infected . But one question is super important : How long will it take for that to happen ? If it happens in a few months , every hospital will be overwhelmed and people will not be treated for coronavirus or other diseases . If it happens that fast , it will be an unprecedented disaster . However , if we do our best in terms of prevention by practicing social distancing , reducing travel , not going to work when we ’re sick , we could slow spread of the disease . If the same 60 - 70 % infection of the global population is spread over 3 years , then hospitals do n’t get overwhelmed , people can get treated , and we have time to develop a vaccine — it ’s a completely different story . The difference between it happening fast or slow is potentially the difference between a 1918 flu level event and a bad flu season level event . We have control over that .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "953aa01e-7538-11ea-9b53-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "953bb788-7538-11ea-af7b-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "953bb86e-7538-11ea-9a0d-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Virus"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869647.800606, "questionText": "How does a virus shift from zoonotic to human - to - human transmission ?", "answerText": "When a virus passes from a nonhuman animal into a human , we call that moment of spillover a zoonotic transmission . It ’s an ecological event . What happens next depends on evolutionary potential and chance . If the virus is adaptable , it may succeed in replicating and proliferating in the new human host . Maybe it kills the person and the line of transmission comes to an end there — as happens with rabies . But if the virus is even more adaptable , it may acquire the ability to pass from one human host to another , perhaps by sexual contact ( as with HIV ) , perhaps in bodily fluids such as blood ( as with Ebola ) , perhaps in respiratory droplets launched by coughing or sneezing ( as with influenza or SARS ) . What makes a virus adaptable ? The changeability of its genome , plus Darwinian natural selection . Those viruses with single - stranded RNA genomes , which replicate themselves inaccurately and therefore have highly changeable genomes , are among the most adaptable . Coronaviruses belong to that group .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "95ad5b4a-7538-11ea-947c-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "95ad5c08-7538-11ea-b87d-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "95ad5c4c-7538-11ea-ae65-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Virus"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869648.551334, "questionText": "Is it possible to be reinfected with the novel coronavirus ?", "answerText": "Reinfection is always a possibility with a viral infection , particularly if you have a subclinical infection and do n’t mount much of an immune response against it . Reinfection is also possible within the window after the first infection and before you develop antibodies . That window can vary from a couple of weeks to a few months , depending on how much your immune system was triggered . We ’ve now got a good population of people who have recovered from the virus . Serum samples from those patients can allow us to time exactly when they begin to develop antibodies and when they develop sufficient titers and neutralizing antibodies . This will help us determine what the window is for protection . Before your immune system returns to normal , you can be infected by not just this virus , but by regular colds and flu . A couple of months may be a reasonable window of recovery , based on what we know right now .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "961fe89a-7538-11ea-b35f-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "961fe962-7538-11ea-a49f-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "961fe9a8-7538-11ea-a067-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Virus"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869649.313257, "questionText": "Can the new coronavirus be transmitted via paper money ?", "answerText": "Cash can be contaminated with potential bacterial pathogens , but there is little information about viruses on cash in general — and nothing about contamination with SARS - CoV-2 , the virus that causes COVID-19 . SARS - CoV-2 is spread by person - to - person contact — not by touching fomites ( objects that may be contaminated with , and help transmit , infectious organisms ) like cash . And , it ’s unclear how long COVID-19 remains viable on surfaces — ranging from a few minutes to hours to potentially days depending on the temperature , humidity and surface type . Switching from cash to plastic has not been proven more protective , either , except perhaps by reducing person - to person hand exposure . Some countries are washing or disinfecting cash , but there is no data demonstrating how this process works . The best practice is social distancing : limiting person - to - person contact by shutting down schools , bars , and other crowded places . That is what will slow infections , prevent health care systems from overloading , and reduce deaths . That is why everyone should do their part and embrace social distancing rather than worrying about using money or credit cards .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "96942b38-7538-11ea-85c7-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "96942bf6-7538-11ea-b0b6-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "96942c3a-7538-11ea-a065-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Virus"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869650.0651898, "questionText": "What is cryptic transmission , and what is its significance in the COVID-19 outbreak ?", "answerText": "Cryptic transmission is the term that is used when there is no direct contact between person 1 shedding the virus and person 2 contracting it . It is an important indicator of community prevalence of a virus . There is essentially enough circulating virus in a community to transmit the same strain of the virus between individuals who are not directly linked . In the case of the COVID-19 outbreak , this term came into the lexicon after University of Washington researchers sequenced the COVID-19 genome from Snohomish County , Washington , which showed a direct genetic link from the first 2 cases in Washington though they had no known contact . This indicated there was significant community spread , and likely evidence the virus had been circulating for weeks by that point . As I noted on Twitter , the key takeaway is this is going to be a critical path for viral transmission given the potential infectivity prior to the manifestation of symptoms — and what will ultimately make it so hard to control the spread of the virus .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9706e79a-7538-11ea-9a8d-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9706e862-7538-11ea-bcf6-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9706e8a8-7538-11ea-9c88-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Virus"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869650.82017, "questionText": "As COVID-19 symptoms mimic those of common cold and flu viruses , how do you know when you should seek testing or special care ?", "answerText": "The symptoms of COVID-19—including fever , cough , and difficulty breathing — are similar to those of other cold and flu viruses . At this moment , the decision to test for COVID-19 in the US depends on both the patient ’s clinical status and what is happening in a particular geographic location . A history of travel , especially international travel to one of the most affected areas , is still important , but this is evolving as the outbreak develops domestically . Close contact with someone who traveled to those areas or with someone who has been diagnosed with COVID-19 are other considerations . \n The evaluation of cold and flu symptoms will often include testing for routine respiratory viruses as well , especially influenza . In general , if you do not have symptoms and would not ordinarily seek medical care based on how you feel now , you do not need evaluation or testing for COVID-19.Preeti N. Malani , MD , MSJ , is the chief health officer and a professor of Medicine in the Division of Infectious Diseases at the University of Michigan .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "977a1b02-7538-11ea-8823-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "977a1bc0-7538-11ea-a876-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "977a1c06-7538-11ea-8ecd-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Virus"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869651.565813, "questionText": "What are the special risks of COVID-19 to pregnant women ?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "97ebe1b0-7538-11ea-9c8d-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "97ebe278-7538-11ea-8a52-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "97ebe2b4-7538-11ea-a2a5-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Virus"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869652.312119, "questionText": "", "answerText": "Given that coronaviruses can cause the common cold , does that mean humans likely have some protection against this new virus ? Or are we immunologically \" naive \" ? Although it ’s possible we could have pre - existing immunity if we were previously infected with “ common cold ” coronaviruses , there is no evidence that this is protective in people exposed to SARS - CoV-2 ( the virus that causes COVID-19 ) . Unless I see data otherwise , I ’d assume that most of us are immunologically “ naive . ” However , although we do n’t know if it ’s relevant to COVID-19 epidemiology , it has been shown that antibodies against SARS - CoV can block infection of cells with SARS - CoV-2 in vitro , so there is the possibility of protective cross - reactive immunity from closely related coronaviruses .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "985dc246-7538-11ea-8598-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "985dc302-7538-11ea-8bfc-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "985dc348-7538-11ea-8019-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Virus"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869653.056426, "questionText": "Given that coronaviruses can cause the common cold , does that mean humans likely have some protection against this new virus ? Or are we immunologically \" naive \" ?", "answerText": "Although it ’s possible we could have pre - existing immunity if we were previously infected with “ common cold ” coronaviruses , there is no evidence that this is protective in people exposed to SARS - CoV-2 ( the virus that causes COVID-19 ) . Unless I see data otherwise , I ’d assume that most of us are immunologically “ naive . ” However , although we do n’t know if it ’s relevant to COVID-19 epidemiology , it has been shown that antibodies against SARS - CoV can block infection of cells with SARS - CoV-2 in vitro , so there is the possibility of protective cross - reactive immunity from closely related coronaviruses .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "98cf54c2-7538-11ea-b6de-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "98cf5576-7538-11ea-b500-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "98cf55ba-7538-11ea-98b2-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Virus"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869653.807175, "questionText": "How do you go about creating a vaccine against a new virus ?", "answerText": "Every virus has its unique challenges . In the case of n - coronavirus , the vaccine challenges are 2-fold . First , you have to interfere with the virus ’s ability to dock with a specific receptor in the lungs called ACE2 . Then , you need to reduce the problem of antibody - dependent enhancement . ADE means that some respiratory virus vaccines can actually make things worse . There are multiple ways to solve this problem . One option is creating a vaccine that only uses parts of the pathogen to stimulate the immune system .   One approach is to do this by producing   recombinant protein subunit vaccines . We have found that these vaccines that use a part of a protein of the virus ( the spike protein ) and known as   the receptor binding domain ( RBD ) are optimal for   2 reasons :   Recombinant proteins are a standard technology that has resulted in other licensed vaccines , including the hepatitis B and HPV vaccines ; and it ’s possible to produce this vaccine in abundance and at low cost .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9941e2e4-7538-11ea-8e13-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9941e3a2-7538-11ea-8c7f-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9941e3e8-7538-11ea-b7c9-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Virus"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869654.551868, "questionText": "", "answerText": "How does this particular coronavirus compare with other coronaviruses like SARS and MERS ? “ We are learning more about the virus every day . On the continuum of the common cold to SARS , it ’s now clear that the novel coronavirus is more contagious than SARS ,   but less deadly . We do n’t yet know how much more contagious , or how much less deadly . The number of confirmed infections with nCoV has already far outpaced the total number of suspected SARS cases . ”", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "99b38480-7538-11ea-a2ee-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "99b3853e-7538-11ea-a7ba-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "99b38586-7538-11ea-9d59-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Virus"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869655.297994, "questionText": "How does this particular coronavirus compare with other coronaviruses like SARS and MERS ?", "answerText": "“ We are learning more about the virus every day . On the continuum of the common cold to SARS , it ’s now clear that the novel coronavirus is more contagious than SARS ,   but less deadly . We do n’t yet know how much more contagious , or how much less deadly . The number of confirmed infections with nCoV has already far outpaced the total number of suspected SARS cases . ”", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9a255e02-7538-11ea-b790-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9a255ed4-7538-11ea-85db-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9a255f1a-7538-11ea-a68e-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Virus"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869656.0427608, "questionText": "There have been news reports that the coronavirus epidemic will last for 18 months or longer and come in multiple waves . If so , how long will social distancing be necessary in that situation ?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9a970278-7538-11ea-abc8-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9a970336-7538-11ea-a204-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9a970374-7538-11ea-ac74-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Outbreak"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869656.777152, "questionText": "What ’s the worst case scenario for this pandemic ?", "answerText": "There is already evidence of widening transmission of SARS - CoV-2 across the Southern Hemisphere , though the virus is currently taking its primary toll in the North . It is likely that 60 - 65 % of Northern Hemisphere populations will be infected with the virus by July or August . As the epidemics seem to diminish later in the summer , action will shift to the South , with COVID-19 sweeping across Latin America , Africa and the South Pacific , similarly infecting upwards of 60 % of populations . And then by December , it will make a slow return to the Northern Hemisphere , creating a North / South cycle that will persist for years .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9b07119e-7538-11ea-a9a4-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9b071270-7538-11ea-9af9-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9b0712b6-7538-11ea-9721-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Outbreak"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869657.504916, "questionText": "How much will mortality rates vary from country - to - country given differing levels of health system preparedness and response resources ?", "answerText": "Mortality rates will vary by country according to several factors . First , it will depend on the age structure of the population ; Italy has the second oldest population in the world , which    may partly explain the high mortality observed . Health care availability ( in terms of the number of hospital and intensive care beds ) and accessibility ( free versus paid ) will also influence mortality . For example , low death rates in Germany and South Korea are partially attributed to the relatively high number of hospital beds per capita . Moreover , disparities in death rates between Hubei province — the location of Wuhan , where the outbreak first emerged — and other parts of China are thought to be due to the rapid case rise and resulting strain on health care resources in Hubei . Lastly , a country ’s testing policy will be an important determining factor . If there is widespread testing of community as well as hospital - based cases , mortality will be lower than if testing was solely focused on hospital cases .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9b761df0-7538-11ea-8e77-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9b761ea4-7538-11ea-acea-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9b761ee8-7538-11ea-99dc-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Outbreak"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869658.239499, "questionText": "When does an outbreak become a pandemic ?", "answerText": "The word pandemic literally means “ all people ” in Greek . But clearly not all people become sick even in the worst pandemics . Epidemiologists typically mean an infectious disease epidemic that has spread or is spreading globally . Usually we refer to a pandemic only when it involves a new disease . So , for example , we talk about an influenza pandemic when there is a new strain of flu spreading around the world . In contrast , we do not refer to the global outbreak of seasonal influenza as a pandemic because the strains are not new . There is no strict definition of when an epidemic becomes a pandemic — but usually it means that the disease is actively spreading on several continents with likely continued spread to other continents .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9be6348c-7538-11ea-9779-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9be63554-7538-11ea-9ce8-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9be63590-7538-11ea-bbf3-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Outbreak"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869658.970133, "questionText": "Why are wild animals believed to be the source of this outbreak ?", "answerText": "About 60 % of newly emerged and re - emerging pathogens share a common origin : the bodies of animals . Genetic and epidemiological evidence suggest that the novel coronavirus , like SARS , may have emerged from a so - called “ wet market , ” where wild species that would rarely encounter each other in nature are crammed together , allowing microbes to spread between species and into humans . China claimed to have cracked down on these markets after the SARS outbreak , but when I visited a few years later , it was n’t hard to find one .  \n But such markets are only part of the problem . The loss of wildlife habitat around the world more generally is forcing wild species to cram into closer proximity to human settlements . Bats , for example , have been fingered as the source of Ebola , SARS , and a host of other pathogens . When we cut down the forests where they live , they come roost in our backyards and farms instead . It ’s this kind of novel , intimate contact that provides opportunities for the microbes that live in their bodies to spread into ours .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9c55b0f0-7538-11ea-9a6a-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9c55b1ae-7538-11ea-8342-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9c55b1e8-7538-11ea-ab7f-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Outbreak"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869659.6945658, "questionText": "How do disease detectives find the source of an outbreak like this ?", "answerText": "Once two or more people are identified , disease detectives ( such as those in the CDC ’s Epidemic Intelligence Service ) look for what these people have in common . Do they live together ? Work together ? Shop at the same market ? Points of overlap could indicate sources of the pathogen . At the same time , infectious disease doctors and scientists try figure out what the pathogen is . In the case of the novel coronavirus , scientists isolated and genetically sequenced the virus , revealing its close relationship to SARS , which originated in bats but was transmitted to humans through another species .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9cc43b24-7538-11ea-a0a9-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9cc43be2-7538-11ea-8179-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9cc43c28-7538-11ea-bb53-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Outbreak"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869660.428221, "questionText": "", "answerText": "What are super spreaders and how can they affect the trajectory of an outbreak ? Rather than using the term super spreaders ( a person who infects a large number of people ) , we should think of them as super spreading events . Maybe a person is at the right time of infection and at the mall . Typhoid Mary infected many people because she was a cook . Part of the reason we stopped SARS is that a lot of super spreading was happening in health care settings and when people really got their act together in terms of infection control and biocontainment , it nipped the epidemic in the bud . Super spreading events have the largest influence an outbreak ’s trajectory early on . If there ’s only a few cases and one person then infects 10 others , it can make it start strong . Once an epidemic gets going and has 100 to 200 cases or more , the “ law of large numbers ” takes over — and it stops mattering so much .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9d342d8a-7538-11ea-b275-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9d342e5c-7538-11ea-b79b-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9d342ea2-7538-11ea-9730-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Outbreak"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869661.166503, "questionText": "What are super spreaders and how can they affect the trajectory of an outbreak ?", "answerText": "Rather than using the term super spreaders ( a person who infects a large number of people ) , we should think of them as super spreading events . Maybe a person is at the right time of infection and at the mall . Typhoid Mary infected many people because she was a cook . Part of the reason we stopped SARS is that a lot of super spreading was happening in health care settings and when people really got their act together in terms of infection control and biocontainment , it nipped the epidemic in the bud . Super spreading events have the largest influence an outbreak ’s trajectory early on . If there ’s only a few cases and one person then infects 10 others , it can make it start strong . Once an epidemic gets going and has 100 to 200 cases or more , the “ law of large numbers ” takes over — and it stops mattering so much .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9da4d4ae-7538-11ea-acc4-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9da4d580-7538-11ea-93e0-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9da4d5c6-7538-11ea-91b8-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Outbreak"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869661.891789, "questionText": "What ’s a reproductive number and what does it tell us about an outbreak ’s future ?", "answerText": "The reproductive number represents the average number of people that one infected person will infect . The reproductive number for a disease can change based on how infectious the pathogen is , the host population , and environmental factors . To control an outbreak , the goal is to reduce a disease ’s reproductive number to less than 1 . If the reproductive number remains 1 or higher , the outbreak will continue . In the case of COVID-19 , the estimated reproductive number is around 2.6 , meaning the outbreak is expected to continue . The reproductive number can be reduced by altering transmission dynamics — with social distancing , home isolation , quarantine , and use of personal protective equipment in health care settings . Over time as people are infected and recover — or if a vaccine becomes available ( which may take months or years)—immunity in the population also reduces the effective reproductive number of a disease .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9e13801e-7538-11ea-848b-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9e1380de-7538-11ea-8bbe-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9e13811a-7538-11ea-baed-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Outbreak"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869662.616959, "questionText": "What does successful risk communications look like ?", "answerText": "When you think of containing an epidemic , from Ebola to coronavirus , labs and disease surveillance are often top of mind . Risk communications , however , is a key aspect in shaping the course of an epidemic , and how prepared people are to combat it . People need timely , accurate and easy - to - understand information that encourages protective behavior without inciting panic . Information based on the changing risk of transmission and not politics , fear or stigma is critical .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9e82271e-7538-11ea-b446-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9e8227e6-7538-11ea-a769-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9e82282c-7538-11ea-9dfb-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Outbreak"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869663.346092, "questionText": "", "answerText": "What are some of the major challenges to global cooperation in this coronavirus outbreak ? Data transparency and political sensitivity are two of the most critical challenges to effective global cooperation on the COVID-19 outbreak — and they are deeply entwined . China has a history of concealing , delaying or refusing to share data and information ( this happened with SARS in 2002 - 2003 and in 2018 , when China reportedly refused to share samples of a bird flu with pandemic potential ) . Leading global health agencies have praised China ’s response to COVID-19 , while other experts doubt the accuracy of the reported data . Data transparency is key to building much - needed trust — and preventing the misallocation of resources , which could slow the response . Some countries in Asia — where China holds significant economic and political influence — have carefully crafted their public coronavirus responses , aware that criticizing China could hinder cooperation . And all stakeholders face a difficult task : balancing effective disease response with the political sensitivity necessary for a successful , cooperative , global response .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9ef168d8-7538-11ea-94f7-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9ef1699e-7538-11ea-8feb-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9ef169e4-7538-11ea-807c-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Outbreak"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869664.069482, "questionText": "What are some of the major challenges to global cooperation in this coronavirus outbreak ?", "answerText": "Data transparency and political sensitivity are two of the most critical challenges to effective global cooperation on the COVID-19 outbreak — and they are deeply entwined . China has a history of concealing , delaying or refusing to share data and information ( this happened with SARS in 2002 - 2003 and in 2018 , when China reportedly refused to share samples of a bird flu with pandemic potential ) . Leading global health agencies have praised China ’s response to COVID-19 , while other experts doubt the accuracy of the reported data . Data transparency is key to building much - needed trust — and preventing the misallocation of resources , which could slow the response . Some countries in Asia — where China holds significant economic and political influence — have carefully crafted their public coronavirus responses , aware that criticizing China could hinder cooperation . And all stakeholders face a difficult task : balancing effective disease response with the political sensitivity necessary for a successful , cooperative , global response .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9f5fca42-7538-11ea-91c3-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9f5fcaf6-7538-11ea-a441-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9f5fcb34-7538-11ea-b86c-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Outbreak"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869664.791063, "questionText": "Could export goods transmit SARS - CoV-2 infection around the world ?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "9fcde506-7538-11ea-a64f-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "9fcde5b8-7538-11ea-b4b4-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "9fcde5f4-7538-11ea-b71a-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Outbreak"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869665.520597, "questionText": "What ’s the most important thing that WHO can do in the fight against COVID-19 ?", "answerText": "WHO has reiterated to all countries that with early and aggressive measures , they can stop transmission and save lives . WHO must be the first entry point for reliable information on the virus and its spread . It also has the unique mandate to provide evidence - based guidance to help countries and individuals to assess and manage their risk and make decisions . This is even more critical now as countries should be preparing for sustained community transmission . WHO must also be able to support the most vulnerable countries . The world requires a comprehensive and coordinated approach as outlined in the Strategic Preparedness and Response Plan that WHO has issued : Establishing international coordination and operational support ; scaling up country readiness and response operations ; and accelerating priority research and innovation . That turns the question on its head : One of the most important things countries and financial organizations must now do is support WHO in order to protect us all .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a03d367a-7538-11ea-8c86-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a03d37ec-7538-11ea-b9f0-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a03d38d2-7538-11ea-bb37-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869666.260399, "questionText": "What does “ preparedness ” in a country really mean ?", "answerText": "Preparedness starts with funding . That ’s how everything else gets done — by having resources available to prepare for these kinds of rare but highly impactful events . Public health departments would use that money to ensure expertise in emergency and pandemic planning . That ’s key not only for the public health preparedness , but for preparedness in hospitals and long - term care facilities as well . The money could also be used for supplies . In the US , we ’ve heard a lot of about the Strategic National Stockpile which contains critical medicines and supplies needed during public health disasters . Having the resources to ensure we have extra supplies on hand is crucial .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a0ae18f4-7538-11ea-9558-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a0ae19b4-7538-11ea-a614-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a0ae19f8-7538-11ea-aefd-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869666.980824, "questionText": "", "answerText": "In the absence of approved treatments , what can health care providers do ?", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a11c068c-7538-11ea-b002-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a11c0758-7538-11ea-8b09-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a11c079c-7538-11ea-a37c-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869667.701935, "questionText": "In the absence of approved treatments , what can health care providers do ?", "answerText": "", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a18a0efe-7538-11ea-9237-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a18a0fb4-7538-11ea-acdc-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a18a0ff8-7538-11ea-b293-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869668.451222, "questionText": "What should the average person in a non - outbreak area be doing to prepare ?", "answerText": "The CDC believes it is likely that COVID-19 will cause a pandemic , but there are steps that the public can take to protect and prepare themselves . First , it is important to stay informed and follow instructions issued by your local or state health department and the CDC . Basic infection control measures still apply in this scenario . Practicing good handwashing techniques or using hand sanitizer , avoiding people who are ill , and staying home when you are sick are all effective measures . A pandemic could interrupt supply chains and result in closures at local businesses , meaning it may be prudent to stock reserves of critical supplies . Examples include extra prescription medications , asthma relief inhalers , over - the - counter anti - fever and pain medications , non - perishable food items , household cleaning supplies , and toiletries . However , do not hoard - this could create shortages .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a1fc6406-7538-11ea-80af-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a1fc6526-7538-11ea-a631-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a1fc6594-7538-11ea-98ce-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869669.1839402, "questionText": "Does the COVID-19 pandemic automatically mean setbacks for ongoing global health programs ?", "answerText": "Consider the limitations or strain already on health systems in many of the countries where global health programs operate . Whether related to health services , surveillance , or supply chains , meeting public demand can be an ongoing challenge at baseline . To add an outbreak response in those settings could spur an outright collapse of essential resources . And that could have a ripple effect for people in need of care across a range of issues , not only those exposed to a novel disease . Consider a woman who can no longer visit a local clinic to protect her from pregnancy complications . Or the person living with HIV , TB , or some other chronic condition who can no longer receive lifesaving medications , either because of a breakdown or diversion of the pipeline intended to provide those . Furthermore , these very populations are at greater risk of poor outcomes from a disease like COVID-19 , creating a potentially vicious cycle . That is why it 's essential that policymakers and practitioners shore up resources that protect progress in other critical areas of global health , while preventing fallout from a new public health enemy . If we are vigilant , we can soften the blow .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a26c31d0-7538-11ea-b728-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a26c328c-7538-11ea-a965-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a26c32d4-7538-11ea-b11c-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869669.912746, "questionText": "How can public health advocates encourage citizens to trust their advice in countries roiled by attacks on science ?", "answerText": "Today ’s communication environment is a sea of rapidly changing “ information , ” confusion and distrust . Events shift rapidly , and conflicting perspectives , opinions and statements and accusations of “ fake news ” are common . Science - based information , when inconvenient , can be contested as just another perspective while repetition is used to establish “ facts . ” In this environment , presenting public health information so it is trusted , understood and acted upon is difficult but possible . Trust is built over time . Establish credibility by being a reliable source over time so when a crisis occurs , people will turn to you . \n Focus on what people want to know ; not just on what you want to communicate . One person ’s important facts can be irrelevant to others . \n Make information accessible . Provide the points and their basis and context clearly . \n Work with others . Similar information stemming from multiple sources strengthens believability and credibility .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a2db66c2-7538-11ea-a953-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a2db68f4-7538-11ea-9571-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a2db6938-7538-11ea-8bf6-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869670.647969, "questionText": "What is the best way to counter misinformation in the media ?", "answerText": "The best way to counter misinformation in the media is with an aggressive onslaught of facts . During an outbreak , information may be shifting , guidance changing , and questions multiplying , but the process is guided by adherence to reality and logic . Uncertainty is not an excuse for entertaining arbitrary assertions offered in defiance of the need for evidence . They should be identified as such and dismissed .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a34b9674-7538-11ea-a0e9-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a34b974c-7538-11ea-9bf4-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a34b978a-7538-11ea-8a57-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869671.372637, "questionText": "", "answerText": "What is it like inside a hospital biocontainment room ? At first glance , patient rooms in the Johns Hopkins Biocontainment Unit look no different than any hospital patient room — until you see the doors . They ’re color - coded for health care worker safety . The colors signify required safety procedures to gain entry to a room . Red , for example , might alert a provider to change their personal protective gear . We work so hard to make sure we can safely care for any patient , at any time , and simple safety cues like our doors help us do just that . The design of the 7,900 square - foot unit , including three patient rooms , an onsite lab , shower facilities and clean - in / clean - out anterooms , helps us care for patients safely while protecting our staff and our community . A patient might be feeling scared and disoriented , so making sure they are safe and cared for is the number one priority of our team .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a3ba29c0-7538-11ea-8fb0-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a3ba2a7e-7538-11ea-8831-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a3ba2aba-7538-11ea-b943-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869672.106049, "questionText": "What is it like inside a hospital biocontainment room ?", "answerText": "At first glance , patient rooms in the Johns Hopkins Biocontainment Unit look no different than any hospital patient room — until you see the doors . They ’re color - coded for health care worker safety . The colors signify required safety procedures to gain entry to a room . Red , for example , might alert a provider to change their personal protective gear . We work so hard to make sure we can safely care for any patient , at any time , and simple safety cues like our doors help us do just that . The design of the 7,900 square - foot unit , including three patient rooms , an onsite lab , shower facilities and clean - in / clean - out anterooms , helps us care for patients safely while protecting our staff and our community . A patient might be feeling scared and disoriented , so making sure they are safe and cared for is the number one priority of our team .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a42a12a8-7538-11ea-9295-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a42a1366-7538-11ea-b634-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a42a13a2-7538-11ea-b1fe-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869672.8323681, "questionText": "What ’s the best way to respond to the coronavirus outbreak ?", "answerText": "Early in a coronavirus outbreak , unknowns are a given . But the global health community ca n’t afford to wait to see if a best- or worst - case scenario unfolds . Some post - haste priorities : Vaccine development : Make this is a top priority . Vaccines can dramatically slow disease spread though they can take at least a year to develop . Plans for large - scale production at different sites worldwide are also needed . \n\n\n Find treatments : Test possible antivirals — such as flu and HIV medications — for treatment options . \n\n\n Expand diagnostic capacity : Manufacture and distribute rapid diagnostic kits so cases can be identified quickly . \n\n\n Boost hospital readiness : Strengthen infection control procedures , train health workers , and keep masks , gowns , and gloves stocked . \n\n Communicate : Share facts ( and unknowns ) clearly with the public , and resist the temptation to withhold bad news . If the virus is ultimately less lethal than feared , or more easily contained , the extra effort will pay off when the next one strikes .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a498e67e-7538-11ea-9ef7-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a498e73a-7538-11ea-885e-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a498e778-7538-11ea-86ab-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869673.556735, "questionText": "What should a country like the US be doing to prepare when an outbreak like this begins to spread globally ?", "answerText": "“ Beginning preparedness activities when an epidemics hits is too late .    Although the US has a   relatively strong   health system , we need to be better prepared for an epidemic , particularly by strengthening state and local health departments and connections with health care providers and facilities . But we ca n’t protect ourselves only within our own borders . Our biggest vulnerability is spread in countries with weak health systems – viruses do n’t need visas . The US should   double down   on support for countries in Africa and Asia so the health workers in these countries can find , stop and prevent epidemics . In the US and globally , there are important and simple things we can do that will prevent illness now and also protect against coronavirus : improve hand hygiene ( handwashing ) , cough hygiene ( cover coughs ) , do n’t expose others if we ’re feeling ill , and improve health care infection control . ”", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a5076e14-7538-11ea-8677-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a5076ed2-7538-11ea-a91d-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a5076f18-7538-11ea-ac38-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869674.295636, "questionText": "Can travel restrictions and quarantines stem the spread of the coronavirus ?", "answerText": "Travel bans ca n’t keep all cases of the virus out of a country . As the epidemic expands , cases may originate in any number of countries . We may already have unrecognized cases in the US . Travel bans can actually make us less safe . They can make countries facing restrictions not want to share information about their outbreaks . They can disrupt the distribution of supplies needed to control the epidemic .   Similarly , as we saw with the US ’s Ebola response in 2014 , quarantining returning travelers makes doctors and nurses less likely to volunteer to serve in affected countries . This virus is likely past the point of containment . We need to focus on mitigating its impact by speeding the development of diagnostic tools , vaccines , and drugs to treat infections .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a5782d70-7538-11ea-b6d6-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a5782e2e-7538-11ea-90a6-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a5782e74-7538-11ea-95b7-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869675.022462, "questionText": "Are strong national health systems all we need for pandemic preparedness ?", "answerText": "Strong health systems are certainly a crucial foundation for preparedness . All countries , rich or poor , need to have a set of core national preparedness capabilities . For example , they need strong surveillance systems in place that can detect infectious diseases with pandemic potential , robust case detection , and effective contact tracing ( i.e. , identifying and reaching those who may have been in contact with an infected person ) . But that ’s only part of the story . By definition , pandemics cross national boundaries — they are global in nature and they require a global response , not just a national one . A whole set of “ transnational ” activities , called global public goods , is another critical plank in pandemic preparedness . These require collective funding by   all   countries . Such goods include developing medical countermeasures like pandemic vaccines , diagnostics , and treatments , stockpiling of medical supplies ( including personal protective equipment ) , and ensuring that there is global “ surge capacity ” to rapidly scale up production and distribution of vaccines .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a5e7150a-7538-11ea-9dad-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a5e715c8-7538-11ea-890d-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a5e71606-7538-11ea-90b5-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869675.7471879, "questionText": "What do frontline health care workers need most when they face an outbreak like this ?", "answerText": "Health care workers are our first line of defense against disease , whether coronavirus or otherwise . In order to safely and effectively do their jobs they need to both have proper training and the right protective equipment . This keeps them safe from infection in “ peace time ” and during a large outbreak like we have now . Health care workers are often the first affected by these types of outbreaks and to some extent can act as a canary in the coalmine for how infectious a new disease outbreak is .    In the past , health care workers have died from infections and also amplified initial cases spreading the outbreak quickly .    If we are to protect health workers and limit transmission , we must do more to ensure the right training and the right equipment are available all the time and not just once an outbreak has started . Health workers are making heroic efforts in China , where they have converged on the epicenter . They can only protect us if they are protected .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a655aaa6-7538-11ea-98f9-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a655ab64-7538-11ea-aca7-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a655aba8-7538-11ea-ad30-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.globalhealthnow.org/2020-02/coronavirus-expert-reality-check", "sourceName": "Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health", "sourceDate": 1583395200, "lastUpdateTime": 1583395200.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "College", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1585869676.4720159, "questionText": "What are the ethical considerations   of using quarantines ?", "answerText": "The tools of public health during   suspected infectious outbreaks include limits or restrictions on the movement   of individual citizens ,   ranging from travel bans , to closure of businesses and   schools , to isolation of individuals in their homes , to forced quarantine in   medical facilities . The goal in   implementing public health measures during suspected outbreaks is to balance   the freedom of   individuals against the restrictions on freedom required to achieve legitimate protections of the public 's health , with   public and transparent justification of policy decisions . Whatever   restrictions are implemented should   be the least restrictive to accomplish the stated public health goals . Quarantine is considered a   measure of last   resort given the severe restrictions it imposes on individual liberty , and when   misused   or ineffective   can severely   undermine   trust in government .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "a6c4443e-7538-11ea-ad09-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "a6c44506-7538-11ea-9db7-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "a6c44542-7538-11ea-bc22-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Response"}
